Guide to the Fedor Stepun Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1917-65; Series II; 8.8; (23 boxes)
  - SHORTER WRITINGS
    - "Zentraler Inhalt des Starrentums [Die Lehre der Hesychasten]": lecture, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1770)
    - "Die Zukunft ist unsere Aufgabe": lecture, holograph, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1771)
    - "Die Zukunftausgabe der deutschen Demokratie": clipping from Suddeutsche Zeitung N44. (3 c.), 1946 May 30 (Box 57, Folder 1772)
    - "Zum hundertsten Geburtstag von Fridtjof Nansen [1961]": article, typescript, initialled (Box 57, Folder 1773)
    - "Zur Geschichte und Theologie der Ikonenverehrung": typescript, corrected, and carbon, corrected. (Box 57, Folder 1774)
    - "Zur Qualifikation Tschizewskijs": clipping, 1949 Apr 4 (Box 57, Folder 1775)
    - "Zur Einführung in das kunstlerische Schaffen Erasmus von Jakimow": typescript, corrected and typescript, carbon, corrected. (Box 57, Folder 1776)
    - "Zur Soziologie und Philosophie des Films": review, clipping, corrected, 1955 Jul 30 (Box 57, Folder 1777)
    - "Zur Theologie der Ikone und Ikonenverehrung": "Ikona i ikonopochitanie": typescript, carbon, corrected, and holograph notes (Box 57, Folder 1778)
    - "Zwei Strömmungen der russischen Literatur"
      - Lecture, holograph, for Würzburg, July 1962, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1779)
      - Holograph., n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1780)
      - Lecture, typescript, carbon, corrected; typescript and holograph notes and draft pp. To have been read at Würzburg on July 14, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 1781)
  - UNTITLED WORKS
    - [Autobiography and personal philosophy]: typescript, carbon, (2 c.) (Box 58, Folder 1782)
    - [N. A. Berdiaev]: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1783)
    - [N. A. Berdiaev and V. I. Ivanov]: holograph fragments and holograph and typescript notes (Box 58, Folder 1784)
    - [Speech on biography]: holograph, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1785)
    - [Biography]: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1786)
    - [Biography]: typescript, carbon, signed, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1787)
    - [Biography]: typescript, carbon, for Bayerischer Rundfunk, with carbon of TL dated Jan 15 1965 (Box 58, Folder 1788)
    - [A. A. Blok]: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1789)
    - [Bolshevism]: fragment of stenographic typescript, holograph on verso, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1790)
    - [I. A. Bunin]: holograph, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1791)
    - [Charity organization for children]: speech, [1961 Feb 2] (Box 58, Folder 1792)
    - [Christianity]: typescript, carbon, corrected. In form of letter or address to Johannes Kühn, 1940 Oct 24 (Box 58, Folder 1793)
    - [Eurasianism]: holograph, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1794)
    - [Film]: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1795)
    - [Gorky]: typescript fragment, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1796)
    - [Graduation]: speech, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1797)
    - [Irinarkh, monk, d. 1616]: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1798)
    - [München, 800th anniversary]: typescript, carbon, corrected; with two informational sheets on event and address, 1958 (Box 58, Folder 1799)
    - [Neue Darmstädter Verlagsanstalt]: transcript of FAS's remarks, 2 typescripts, carbon, corrected; with ALS and 2 TLS concerning publication, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 1800)
    - [ Novyi grad ]: article, typescript, carbon, corrected. Verso includes unused notices of 75th birthday, 1960 Apr 3 (Box 58, Folder 1801)
    - [Orthodox paschal liturgy]: typescript, carbon, corrected; and typescript, carbon, corrected, signed (Box 58, Folder 1802)
    - [Orthodox paschal liturgy]: typescript, carbon, corrected, signed, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1803)
    - [B. L. Pasternak]: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1804)
    - [A. S. Pushkin]: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1805)
    - [A. M. Remizov]: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1806)
    - [Russia and Europe]: holograph (Box 58, Folder 1807)
    - [Russian emigration]: holograph, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1808)
    - [Russian religious thought]: holograph, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1809)
    - [Russian spiritual history]: notes, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1810)
    - [V. S. Solov'ev]: for radio, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1811)
    - [V. S. Solov'ev]: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1812)
    - [Symbolism]: holograph, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1813)
    - [Tchaikovsky's "Evgenii Onegin"]: typescript, carbon, annotated, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1814)
    - [Technology]: speech, holograph, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1815)
    - [Technology]: speech, printed version, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 1815a)
    - [Theater and film]: speech, holograph (Box 58, Folder 1816)
    - [Theater and film]: typescript, carbon carbon, corrected (Box 58, Folder 1817)
    - [D. I. Tschizewskij]: typescript, carbon, and holograph (Box 58, Folder 1818)
    - [D. I. Tschizewskij]: article, published in Rhein-Neckar-Zeitung, photostat, 1959 Apr 5 (Box 58, Folder 1819)
  - RESEARCH NOTES
    - Binder
      The following 21 folders of notes are listed as they were filed together, presumably by FAS; alphabetical classification is retained and noted in parentheses
      - "Razmyshlenie ob Erose": holograph 1 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1820)
      - Lecture notes ("F") 2 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1821)
      - Notes on Fedotov ("F") 3 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1822)
      - S.L.Frank, Realnost' i chelovek ("F") 4 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1823)
      - Translation of Sonnet 34 by F. Petrarca by V. I. Ivanov: typescript carbon ("F") 5 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1824)
      - Poem from Ivanov's Rimskii dnevnik 1944 g.: typescript ("F") 6 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1825)
      - Pg 15 from "Perepiska S.L. Franka s Viach. Ivanovym": typescript, carbon, corrected. Publ. Mosty. ("F") 7 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1826)
      - Pg 11 of "Perepiska": typescript carbon; Poem from Ivanov's Rimskii dnevnik 1944 g. ("J") 8 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1827)
      - Partial translation of Ivanov's "Lermontov": typescript carbon; Deshart, O., "Viacheslav Ivanov biograficheskie zametki" (last page of typescript). ("J") 9 of 21 (Box 59, Folder 1828)
      - Notes on V.I. Ivanov's Po zvezdam: ("J") 10 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1829)
      - "Palinodiia" (from Ivanov's Svet vechernii ): typescript, carbon. ("J") 11 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1830)
      - Notes on Leont'ev: typescript, corrected. ("L") 12 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1831)
      - Notes on Leontovisch's Geschichte des Liberalismus in Russland: ("L") 13 of 21 (Box 59, Folder 1832)
      - Notes on A.M. Remizov's Podstrizhennymi glazami ("R") 14 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1833)
      - Notes on R. Rössler, Voraussetzungen und Grundlagen der Objektivationsidee N. A. Berdjajews (1951): holograph ("R") 15 of 21 (Box 59, Folder 1834)
      - Advertisement for S.M. Solov'ev's Sobranie Sochinenii: photocopy ("S") 16 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1835)
      - Notes on Vl. Solovyov ("S") 17 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1836)
      - Notes on Leonore Ebreo (writer or subject of writer?) ("St") 18 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1837)
      - Notes on Leo Tolstoy ("T") 19 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1838)
      - Notes, unidentified and on V.I. Ivanov's "Tolstoi i kul'tura" ("T") 20 of 21 (Box 59, Folder 1839)
      - Notes excerpted from Zhurnal Moskovskoi Patriarkhii: typescript, corrected. ("Z") 21 of 21, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1840)
    - Loose Notes
      - Notes from: A. Bely, Mezhdu dvukh revoliutsii; Literaturnoe nasledstvo v. 27-8; Paul Tillich, re. symbol; misc. notes and MSS about symbolism, with verso sides including notice of 80th birthday, typescript page from Mystische Weltschau and from typescript by IUrii Ivask (Box 59, Folder 1841)
      - Notes from: N. A. Berdiaev, Philosophie des freien Geistes, Samopoznanie, "(Eskhatologicheskaia) (Ekstentsial'naia) metafizika", Filosofiia svobodnogo dukha, Naznachenie cheloveka; R. Rössler, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1842)
      - "Die Unbekannte" by Alexander Blok: typescript, carbon (Box 59, Folder 1843)
      - Holograph fragment on Blok, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1844)
      - Notes from N. Brodskii,; on German and Russian literary ties (Box 59, Folder 1845)
      - Notes from: G. Florovskii, Puti russkogo bogosloviia; unidentifed notes, including letter fragment dated 1947 Mar 15, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1846)
      - Typescript notes on Germany and Russia (Box 59, Folder 1847)
      - Notes from Igor von Glasenapp: in re Karamzin, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1848)
      - "Werke von Wenceslas Iwanow": typescript, carbon, annotated, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1849)
      - Misc. notes, in re V. I. Ivanov and others (Box 59, Folder 1850)
      - Note in re Maiakovskii and Esenin (Box 59, Folder 1851)
      - Holograph notes from Marco von Pallis, "...Problem des Bosen"; S. Vitte, Vospominaniia; Humanism, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1852)
      - Excerpts of poems by Pushkin, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1853-1854)
      - Typescript fragment on pre- revolutionary Russia, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1855)
      - Notes on Russia; with fragment of outgoing letter, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1856)
      - Typescript fragment on 17th century Russia; from lecture series "Russland und Europa" [?] (Box 59, Folder 1857)
      - Notes on Oswald Spengler, 1962 (Box 59, Folder 1858)
      - Note on Symbolism, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1859)
      - Notes in re Leo Tolstoy, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1860)
      - Unidentified notes on verso of letter from Manz Verlag, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1861)
      - Misc. typescripts on books: annotated, in re Joseph Lortz, Bernhard Bavink, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1862)
      - Bibliography from work by F. S. C. Northrop, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1863)
      - Misc. notations (Box 59, Folder 1864)
    - Notebooks
      - Concerning: V. Maiakovsky, S. Esenin; F. Dostoyevsky; N. Berdiaev, Existentialism; Solovyov and Sophia Divine Wisdom; P. IA. Chaadaev; D. S. Merezhkovsky; misc. Russian history and culture. Notes from P. Annenkov, L. P. Karsavin, Bem, G. Voloshin, N. A. Berdiaev, Zenta Maurina, Evraziiskii vremennik, Voprosy ekonomiki. (Box 60, Folder 1865)
      - Concerning: Leo Tolstoy, V chem moia vera, Ispoved'; Romain Rolland; Bunin; European thought. Notes from: Leo Tolstoy, V chem moia vera, Ispoved', TSarstvo Bozhie vnutri nas, Thomas Mann, "Goethe und Tolstoi"; V. Ivanov, "Krizis individualizma", "Dve stikhii v simvolizme"; G. Fedotov, "Tragediia intelligentsii" (Box 60, Folder 1866)
      - "Vypiski": Notes from G[?], "Bolschewismus als Weltgefabe"; S. J. Skomorowitsch; Achrimow; N. Bucharin; Merezhkovsky, "Poslednie sviatye", "Rossiia i revoliutsiia"; Berdiaev, Die Philosophie des freien Geistes; Der Sinn des Schaffens; Maksim Gorky, Blok, Zaitsev on Chekhov; A. Just, "Russland und Europa"; L. Fischer; misc., [1952?] (Box 60, Folder 1867)
      - Notes from: Solovyov; Pasternak, Doktor Zhivago. Concerning: Blok. Misc. addresses and notations (Box 60, Folder 1868)
      - Concerning: A. Bely, A. Blok, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1869)
      - "Blok v[on] Stepun", n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1870)
      - Concerning: Filmkongress (1952 May 14-21), "Der Untertan nach dem Roman von Heinrich Mann..."; "Über Tragik, Komik und Humor"; Esenin; Maiakovsky; Leonov; Dostoyevsky, Besy. Notes from: "Goethe und das Tragische"; V. Ivanov, Dostojewskij; Georg Simmel; Gregor, "Das Zeitalter des Films"; W. Panofsky; TSvetaeva, "Iskusstvo pri svete sovesti" (Box 60, Folder 1871)
      - Concerning: Solovyov; Il'in, "Wesen und Eigenart der russischer [?]"; Goethe; Grabowsky, "Bolschewismus"; Vestnik akademii nauk SSR; G. Weber, "Die poetische Emigration"; A. Kerensky; Slavophiles; M. Gorlik, "Goethe in Russland"; H. Martin; Soviet literature and philosophy; Church history (Box 60, Folder 1872)
      - Notes from: A. Bely, Nachalo veka, Kubok metelei, Maski, Simvolizm; K. Mochul'skii, Belyi; Misc. notes, including loose leaves, one with typescript of "Revnost'" on verso, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1873)
      - Notes on sociology. Notes from N. Berdiaev, Philosophie des freien Geistes, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1874)
  - REVIEWS
    - Arsen'ev, N. S. Iz russkoi kul'turnoi i tvorcheskoi traditsii (Posev, 1959): typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1875)
    - Berdiajew, Nikolai. Selbsterkenntnis (Darmstadt and Genf: Holle Verlag, 1953): for radio typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 61, Folder 1876)
    - Deutscher, Isaac. Stalin. Die Geschichte des modernen Russlands (Stuttgart: W. Kohlhammer Verlag, 1951): typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 61, Folder 1877)
    - Eckhardt, Hans von. Russischer Christentum: for radio typescript, carbon, corrected, signed, 1948 Nov 15 (Box 61, Folder 1878)
    - Jelagin, Georg: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1879)
    - Eltschaninow, Vater Alexander. Aufzeichnungen (Hamburg and München: Verlag Heinrich Ellerman, 1964):
      - Typescript, carbon, signed, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1880)
      - Typescript, corrected, and holograph. Notation: "okolo 150 strok v gazete" (Box 61, Folder 1881)
    - Frank, S. L. Die Realität und der Mensch. Eine Metaphysik des menschlichen Seins (Paris: YMCA-Press, 1956 [russisch]): typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 61, Folder 1882)
    - Heiseler, Henry von: for radio, typescript, carbon, corrected. Entitled "Mozartsche Musik als Erscheinungsform der russischen Seele", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1883)
    - Ianovskii, V. S. Chelyust' emigranta (New York: Dialog): typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1884)
    - Ivanov, V. I. Svet vechernii (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1962)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1885)
      - Offprints from Novyi zhurnal #75 (3 c.), 1964 (Box 61, Folder 1886)
    - Keenan, George F. Amerika und Russlands Zukunft: typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 61, Folder 1887)
    - Leontowitsch, V. Geschichte des Liberalismus in Russland: two typescript carbons, one corrected, and carbon of TL to unidentified recipient signed by FAS's secretary and dated 1955 Mar 16 (Box 61, Folder 1888)
    - Mackiewicz, Josef. Der Weg ins Nirgendwo (München: Bergstadtverlag): typescript, carbon. (Box 61, Folder 1889)
    - Mackiewicz, Stanislaw. Der Spieler seines Lebens, F.M. Dostojewskij (Zürich: Thomas Verlag, 1952): typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1890)
    - Maurina, Zenta. Dostojewskij, Menschengestalter und Gottsucher (Memmingen: Maxililian Dietrich Verlag, 1952): typescript, carbon (Box 61, Folder 1891)
    - Maurina, Zenta. 'Die Weite Fahrt'. Eine Passion. Memmingen: Maximilian Dietrich Verlag, 1952)
      - Typescript, corrected, signed., n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1892)
      - Clipping from Lug ins Land [?]" (3 c.), 1952 Feb 28 (Box 61, Folder 1893)
    - Rzhevskii, L. Pakazavshemu nam svet " typescript carbons, one corrected, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1894)
    - Schultze, Bernhard. Russische Denker. Ihre Stellung zu Christus, Kirche und Papstum (Wien: Thomas-Moru-Press im Herder Verlag, 1950).
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, and typescript, carbon of radio text (Box 61, Folder 1895)
      - Entitled "Das geistliches Antlitz Russlands", clipping, (2 c.), 1950 Dec 12 (Box 61, Folder 1896)
    - Seraphim, Metropolit. Die Ostkirche (Stuttgart: W. Spemann): typescript, carbon. Radio, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1897)
    - Shcherbatov, Kniaz' Sergei. Khudozhnik v ushedshei Rossii. (Izdatel'stvo imeni Chekhova)": typescript, and carbon (Box 61, Folder 1898)
    - S.L. Frank: 1877-1950 (Miunkhen, 1954): typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1899)
    - Solowjew, Wladimir. Deutsche Gesamtausgabe. Herausgegeben von W. Szylkarski" (Freiburg: Erich Wewel Verlag): typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1900)
    - Stanislavskii, K. S. Rabota aktera nad soboi: holograph, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1901)
    - Tkhorzhevskii, Ivan. Russkaia literatura (Parizh: Vozrozhdenie, 1950): typescript, corrected, signed. Published in Vozrozhdenie 20 (Mar- April 1952), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1902)
    - Weidlé, Wladimir. Russland. Weg und Abweg (Stuttgart: Deutsche Verlags- anstalt, 1956): typescript, carbon. (2 c.). Radio (Box 61, Folder 1903)
    - Zurov, Leonid. Mar'ianka (Paris: 1958): typescript, carbon, 1959 Apr 29 (Box 61, Folder 1904)
    - Miscellaneous, including: Nicolai von Bubnoff and Hans Ehrenberg. Östliches Christentum: Die russischen Philosophen; Leo Zander. re. Dostoevskii; Roman Rössler, re. Berdiaev; Wladimir Weidlé. Russland. Weg und Abweg: typescript, carbon, corrected, entitled "Neues von Russland (Box 61, Folder 1905)
  - COURSE LECTURES
    - "Geistige Beziehungen zwischen Russland und Europa"
      - Misc. holograph and typescript notes; holograph draft incl. parts II, VIII, VI, VII (Box 62, Folder 1906)
      - Holograph draft incl. parts II, III, "Gogol", n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1907)
      - Holograph draft incl. parts II, III, IV, V, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1908)
      - Holograph draft incl parts I, VIII, I, II, IX, I, VII ("Dostojewskij"), fragments on Count A. G. Stroganoff and Zhukovskii. (Box 62, Folder 1909)
    - "Russland und Europa"
      - Holograph draft of IV, VIII, VI, X ("Bakunin"), IV ("Danilewskij", "Faust des Westes"); and "Hauptprobleme der russischer Soziologie" VI (Box 62, Folder 1910)
      - "Namen und Literarausgaben"; holograph drafts incl. parts III, II, VIII, XIII (Box 62, Folder 1911)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts X, IX, VIII, XIII; misc. holograph fragments, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1912)
      - Holograph and typescripts (Box 62, Folder 1913)
      - Holograph drafts (Box 62, Folder 1914)
    - "Die russische Literatur des 20.Jahrhunderts"
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts I, IV, III, II, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1915)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts X, XI, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1916)
    - "Geschichte der russischen Literatur"
      - III ("Der Inhalt der Silben Taube und Peterburgs"), VI, VIII, VII, X, V ("Russische Literatur des 20. Jahrhunderts") (Box 63, Folder 1917)
      - X ("Russische Literatur des 20. Jahrhunderts"), VIII ("Alexander Blok"), IX ("Die Futuristen"), II (Die Geschichtsphilosophie Iwanows") (Box 63, Folder 1918)
    - "Die Geschichte der russischen Philosophie"
      - Holograph drafts of I-VII, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1919)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts VII, X, XI, XII, IX, and misc. notes (Box 63, Folder 1920)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts X, XII, XIII, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1921)
      - Misc. typescript and holograph notes (Box 63, Folder 1922)
    - "Dostojewskij"
      - Notes, "Gogol' i Selo Stepanchikovo", holograph drafts incl. parts IX ("Der Idiot"), VII, VI, II, XX, IX, V, VIII. On verso are some pages of "Vergangenes und Unvergängliches" typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 63, Folder 1923)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts V, IV, III, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1924)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts II, I, VII, VIII. On verso are some pages of "Vergangenes und Unvergängliches": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 63, Folder 1925)
    - "Bolschewismus als kultursoziologisches Problem"
      - Holograph and typescripts incl. parts IX, VII, V, III (Box 63, Folder 1926)
      - Holograph drafts, incl. parts III-V, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1927)
      - Typescript notes, 1956 Jun (Box 63, Folder 1928)
    - "Soziologie der russischen Revolution"
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts IV, V, VI, VIII, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1929)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts IX-XIV, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1930)
    - "Hauptprobleme der russischer Soziologie"
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts I-IV, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1931)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts V-X, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1932)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts XI-XIV, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1933)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts I-III, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1934)
    - "Tolstoi und Solowjew"
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts II, VI, VIII, VII, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1935)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts V, IV, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1936)
      - Holograph drafts incl. parts II, IX; typescript fragment, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1937)
      - Holograph drafts, incl. parts VIII, III, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1938)
    - "Solowjow und Berdjajew"
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, of "Mystische Weltschau"; and holograph, incl. parts I, XII (Box 65, Folder 1939)
      - Typescript, carbon re. N. A. Berdiaev; "Solowjow und das Judentum": typescript, carbon; typescript fragments (Box 65, Folder 1940)
      - Holograph incl. parts XIII, III, VIII, IV, V, IX, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1941)
      - Misc. holograph and typescript pages (Box 65, Folder 1942)
- Organizational Affiliations, 1952-64; Series III; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  Organizational Affiliations are organized by name of organization and, within that, by type of records.
  - TOLSTOY FOUNDATION
    - Correspondence
      - Letters from FAS
        - TL to Elsie Thomas, 1961 Sep 17 (Box 66, Folder 1943)
        - TLS to unidentified newspaper: with letter from 1960 Nov 15 from Vera Samsonova, text of letter and address from President Eisenhower in English, German (4 c.), and Russian, and text of article in English and Russian, 1960 Nov 18 (Box 66, Folder 1944)
      - Letters to FAS
        - ALS and TLS from Alexander Koltschak (Kolchak), 1959 Sep 23, 1961 Oct 3 (Box 66, Folder 1945)
        - From B. Freiherr von Richthofen, 1957-64 (Box 66, Folder 1946)
        - TLS from Vera A. Samsonova, 1961 Feb 1, 1961 Oct 20 (Box 66, Folder 1947)
        - From Tatiana Schaufuss: includes with enclosed copies of letters from Schaufuss to Walter Rinke (1958 Mar 5), Lasch (1958 Jul 18), Emmendorfer (1958 Jul 29),and Wolfrum (1958 Jul 23), [1952]-62 (Box 66, Folder 1948)
        - From Elsie S. Thomas: includes copy of letter from Thomas to A. Maximadshy, with photostat, 1956-64 (Box 66, Folder 1949)
        - TLS from Lidiia Tremel' (Box 66, Folder 1950)
        - TL from R. Winkel [?], 1958 Feb 4 (Box 66, Folder 1951)
      - Third party correspondence
        - TL from Paritätischer Wohlfahrtsverband" to Tolstoy Foundation, 1959 Jun 1 (Box 66, Folder 1952)
        - TL from Walter Rinke to Frau Dr. Maxsein, 1958 Jan 13 (Box 66, Folder 1953)
        - TL from Dr. Walter Rinke to Prof. Dr. Oberlander, 1958 Jan 23 (Box 66, Folder 1954)
        - TL from Tatiana Schaufuss to Dr. M. Kornrumpf, 1961 Sep 12 (Box 66, Folder 1955)
        - TL from Tatiana Schaufuss to Pfarrer Rathgeber with holograph note to FAS, 1959 Oct 28 (Box 66, Folder 1956)
        - TLS from Tatiana Schaufuss to Walter Rinke with enclosed "Erklaerung zu dem Kostenvoranschlag fuer die Veroeffentlichung des "Tolstoy Foundation Nachtichten" Blattes, 1958 Jan 17 (Box 66, Folder 1957)
    - Reports
      - "Kurzer Bericht ueber die Taetigkeit der Tolstoy Foundation, Inc": typescript, carbon (Box 66, Folder 1958)
      - "Entwurf. Tätigkeitsbericht der Tolstoy Foundation, Inc.": typescript, annotated, with drawings, [1957] (Box 66, Folder 1959)
      - "Kurzer Tätigkeitsbericht über die Wohlfahrsarbeit der Tolstoy Foundation": typescript, carbon, 1957 Feb 10 (Box 66, Folder 1960)
      - Reports on activity in Germany: typescript, carbon, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 1961)
      - "Gesamtbericht von Frau Schaufuss über die Arbeit der Tolstoy Foundation im Jare 1957": typescript, carbon (Box 66, Folder 1962)
      - "Memorandum. Bauvorhaben in Klagenfurt - Gesterreich": mimeograph, 1958 Jan 30 (Box 66, Folder 1963)
      - "Satzungen der Tolstoy Foundation in Deutschland": brochure (Box 66, Folder 1964)
    - Minutes
      - For 1956 Nov 15, [c.1956 Nov 15] (Box 66, Folder 1965)
      - For 1957 Feb 12, [c.1957 Feb 12] (Box 66, Folder 1966)
      - For 1957 March 7, [c.1957 Mar 7] (Box 66, Folder 1967)
      - For meeting, incomplete, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1968)
      - For 1957 Dec 10, [c.1957 Dec 10] (Box 66, Folder 1969)
      - For 1959 Feb 9, [c.1959 Feb 9] (Box 66, Folder 1970)